<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-21T11:43:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">RX2Solutions.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">Top 5 things to look for in a Candidate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Top-5-things-to-look-for-in-a-Candidate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top 5 things to look for in a Candidate" /><published>2023-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Top-5-things-to-look-for-in-a-Candidate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Top-5-things-to-look-for-in-a-Candidate.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top 5 things to look for in a Candidate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering candidates for a position, it’s essential to keep in mind a few key factors. Here are the top 5 things we recommend looking for: &lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1. Relevant experience&lt;/strong&gt;: Look for candidates who have experience in the same or similar role. This shows that they have a good understanding of what the position entails and can hit the ground running.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. Strong communication skills&lt;/strong&gt;: Communication is key in any job, so look for candidates who are articulate, clear, and confident in their ability to express themselves.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;3. Adaptability&lt;/strong&gt;: The ability to adapt to changing circumstances and take on new challenges is essential in today’s fast-paced work environment. Look for candidates who are flexible and can think on their feet.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4. Team player&lt;/strong&gt;: No matter what the role, it’s important to work well with others. Look for candidates who are collaborative, supportive, and can work effectively in a team.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;5. Positive attitude&lt;/strong&gt;: A positive attitude can go a long way in creating a productive and enjoyable work environment. Look for candidates who are enthusiastic, motivated, and have a can-do attitude.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you or anyone you know is currently looking for work or is looking for hiring assistance, RX2 Solutions is here to help. Feel free to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt; or 610.340.3490 to discuss how we can be of service to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Top 5 things to look for in a Candidate When considering candidates for a position, it’s essential to keep in mind a few key factors. Here are the top 5 things we recommend looking for:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Turns 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Celebrating-5-Years.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Turns 5" /><published>2023-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Celebrating-5-Years</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Celebrating-5-Years.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celebrating 5 Years&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As we hit our 5th Anniversary, we want to thank everyone for the past five years. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Starting RX2 Solutions has been a humbling, exciting, and life-changing experience. We are grateful to our families and friends for the support they have shown us, our fantastic team, and the relationships and connections we have made throughout our lives. We would not be here today if it weren’t for you. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Here’s to seeing you when we turn ten! &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://rx2solutions.com/assets/images/Phillies.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks, &lt;br /&gt;
Rob &amp;amp; Ross &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">Celebrating 5 Years As we hit our 5th Anniversary, we want to thank everyone for the past five years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fun Fall Recipes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Fun-Fall-Recipes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fun Fall Recipes" /><published>2023-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Fun-Fall-Recipes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/26/Fun-Fall-Recipes.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again when everyone is looking for Fun Fall Recipes! Well, look no further, as RX2 Solutions 
has highlighted some of our staffs favorite Fall Treats!
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/whoopie.png&quot; alt=&quot;Whoopie Pie&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Whoopie Pie&lt;/strong&gt;
These pumpkin whoopie pies are the perfect fall treat! Each soft and fluffy cookie is filled with a creamy maple cream cheese filling that will leave you wanting more. You won’t be able to resist these scrumptious pumpkin whoopie pies! Follow the link for the full recipe &amp;amp; notes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodfolksandfun.net/pumpkin-whoopie-pies/&quot;&gt;https://foodfolksandfun.net/pumpkin-whoopie-pies/&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/RIP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Graveyard Halloween Brownies&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Graveyard Halloween Brownies&lt;/strong&gt;
Graveyard Halloween brownies are a spooky and delicious treat that will delight kids and adults. Serve them on a dark and eerie platter for a creepy dessert experience that will leave your guests screaming for more. Follow the link for the full recipe &amp;amp; notes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/halloween-graveyard-brownies/&quot;&gt;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/halloween-graveyard-brownies&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Pumpkin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Bread&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Bread&lt;/strong&gt;
Pumpkin chocolate chip bread is a delightful autumn-inspired treat that combines the warm flavors of pumpkin and cinnamon with the sweetness of chocolate chips. Whether served warm with a dollop of whipped cream or toasted with a pat of butter, this bread is a perfect dessert or snack for any fall occasion. Follow the link for the full recipe &amp;amp; notes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-bread/&quot;&gt;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-bread/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cookie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spider Cookies&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Spider Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;
Chocolate chip spider cookies are a fun and playful twist on a classic favorite. These cookies are made with a classic chocolate chip cookie base with extra chips added on top, and chocolate legs that are piped on. This recipe is sure to be a crowd-pleaser because who doesn’t love chocolate chip cookies? Follow the link for the full cookie recipe &amp;amp; notes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/chocolate-chip-spider-cookies/&quot;&gt;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/chocolate-chip-spider-cookies/&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/dip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Buffalo Chicken Dip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Buffalo Chicken Dip&lt;/strong&gt;
Buffalo chicken dip is a delicious and flavorful appetizer that is perfect for any party or gathering. The tangy and zesty flavor of the buffalo sauce combined with the creamy and cheesy texture of the dip creates a mouthwatering taste that is sure to please any crowd. Whether you’re hosting a game day party or just looking for a tasty snack, buffalo chicken dip is the perfect choice! Follow the link for the full dip recipe &amp;amp; notes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/buffalo-chicken-dip/&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/buffalo-chicken-dip/&quot;&gt;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/halloween-graveyard-brownies&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/BBQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BBQ Meatballs&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;BBQ Meatballs&lt;/strong&gt;
Nothing says fall more than football! This is the perfect appetizer for all your Eagles watch parties or tailgating at The Linc. This simple recipe is sure to be a crowd-pleaser at your next gathering! Follow the link for the full recipe &amp;amp; notes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/slow-cooker-cranberry-bbq-meatballs/&quot;&gt;https://tastesbetterfromscratch.com/slow-cooker-cranberry-bbq-meatballs/&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><summary type="html">It’s that time of year again when everyone is looking for Fun Fall Recipes! Well, look no further, as RX2 Solutions has highlighted some of our staffs favorite Fall Treats!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Q4 2023 Hiring &amp;amp; Economic Outlook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/20/Q3-2023-Hiring-&-Economic-Outlook.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Q4 2023 Hiring &amp; Economic Outlook" /><published>2023-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/09/20/Q3%202023%20Hiring%20&amp;%20Economic%20Outlook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/09/20/Q3-2023-Hiring-&amp;-Economic-Outlook.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Q4 2023 Hiring &amp;amp; Economic Outlook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q4 looks like it will be similar to Q2 and Q3 with no dramatic changes.  With the end of Summer and the start of budget season, we have seen the demand for hiring increase across all of our lines of business.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
More and more economists, including those at Bank of America, believe there will either be a soft landing or a minor recession&lt;sup&gt;i&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Interest rates have increased half a point since May, which demonstrates a slowdown of rate increases.  With three meetings remaining in 2023, the Fed has hinted that they may raise rates again, but they may not need to or want to if inflation continues to cool&lt;sup&gt;ii&lt;/sup&gt;.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The unemployment rate rose .3% to 3.8% and is still considered better than the full employment rate of 4.0%.  There were an additional 514,000 people who became unemployed in August, however there were also an additional 740,000 people who entered or re-entered the workforce so there were around 200,000 new jobs created even though unemployment went up&lt;sup&gt;iii&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Inflation rose .6% in August and 3.7% year over year with transportation costs such as fuel and airfare being major factors for the increase&lt;sup&gt;iv&lt;/sup&gt;.  While 3.7% is better than where we were towards the middle of the Pandemic, its still significantly above the Fed’s 2% target which may lead to future rate increases in the near term. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In Q4, holiday spending is always a big economic factor and according to Bain Capital, it looks like we will have one of the slowest holiday shopping seasons of the past 10 years with the main factor for this being inflation increasing everyday costs&lt;sup&gt;v&lt;/sup&gt;.  A slowdown in consumer spending may be a positive as it may lead to inflation continuing to drop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We see the economy remaining strong through the remainder of 2023 and into 2024 with strong demand for labor combined with full employment.  If you’d like to discuss your hiring strategy with RX2 Solutions and how we can play a part in it, feel free to reach out – &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt;, 610.340.3490.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;be&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
____________________________ &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;i&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2023/08/04/what-predictions-of-a-soft-landing-no-recession-mean-for-you.html&quot;&gt;www.cnbc.com/2023/08/04/what-predictions&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;ii&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/will-the-fed-raise-rates-again-and-push-cd-returns-even-higher-7853011&quot;&gt;www.investopedia.com/will-the-fed&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;iii&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/news.release/pdf/empsit.pdf&quot;&gt;www.bls.gov/news.release&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;iv&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/cea/written-materials/2023/09/13/the-august-2023-consumer-price-index&quot;&gt;www.whitehouse.gov/cea/written&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;v&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bain.com/insights/2023-holiday-shopping-outlook-infographic/&quot;&gt;www.bain.com/insights&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/be&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">RX2 Solutions Q4 2023 Hiring &amp;amp; Economic Outlook Q4 looks like it will be similar to Q2 and Q3 with no dramatic changes. With the end of Summer and the start of budget season, we have seen the demand for hiring increase across all of our lines of business. More and more economists, including those at Bank of America, believe there will either be a soft landing or a minor recessioni.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Timeless Fourth of July Home Celebrations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/Timeless-Fourth-of-July-Home-Celebrations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Timeless Fourth of July Home Celebrations" /><published>2023-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/Timeless%20Fourth%20of%20July%20Home%20Celebrations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/Timeless-Fourth-of-July-Home-Celebrations.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeless Fourth of July Home Celebrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fourth of July is a time-honored holiday in the United States, and while public gatherings and events are fantastic, celebrating the 4th at home with friends and family can be just as memorable and eventful! Here are five timeless Fourth of July home celebrations that you can enjoy with your family and friends at home:  &lt;!--more--&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backyard BBQ:&lt;/strong&gt; Fire up the grill and host a classic backyard barbecue! Prepare a feast of hamburgers, hot dogs, grilled corn, and barbecue chicken. Set up tables with patriotic décor; anything red, white, and blue will do!  Invite guests to bring their favorite side dishes or dessert to share. Enjoy great food, laughter, and the company of family and friends in the comfort of your backyard.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patriotic Potluck:&lt;/strong&gt; Host a patriotic potluck where everyone contributes a dish inspired by American cuisine. From apple pie and fried chicken to macaroni and cheese, let the classic flavors of the United States shine! Set the party’s tone with patriotic decorations such as balloons, streamers, and flags. Organize a friendly competition for the best red, white, and blue-themed dessert with small prizes for the winners. This potluck is a fantastic way to bond over food and celebrate the spirit of the Fourth of July! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outdoor Movie Night:&lt;/strong&gt; Transform your backyard into an outdoor cinema for an unforgettable Fourth of July movie night. Set up a large screen or hang a white sheet and use blankets and cushions for seating. Choose a selection of patriotic films, such as “Independence Day” or “Born on the Fourth of July,” or opt for a timeless American movie like “Forrest Gump” or “The Sandlot.” Serve popcorn, ice cream, and other movie snacks, and let the movie magic transport you to a world of entertainment and celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crafts and Decorations:&lt;/strong&gt; Involve your family and friends in a creative Fourth of July arts &amp;amp; craft session! Create homemade flags, paper lanterns, or patriotic wreaths using red, white, and blue materials. Inspire children to design and decorate their patriotic t-shirts with fabric paints and markers. These crafts can serve as cherished decorations for you &amp;amp; your family’s home and add a personal touch to your 4th of July celebrations. It’s an opportunity to create memories, unleash creativity, and reflect on the holiday’s significance.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fireworks in the Yard:&lt;/strong&gt; While public fireworks displays are a hallmark of the Fourth of July, you can create your own fireworks show in your backyard. Small fireworks such as fountains, sparklers, and poppers are great options for the backyard. Gather your friends and family in a safe area and enjoy watching your personal firework show! (Be sure to check your local regulations and safety guidelines before purchasing and setting off fireworks, and don’t forget to have a bucket of water nearby to extinguish the fireworks properly!) This personal fireworks experience can be a magical and exciting finale to your home 4th of July celebration!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, regardless of the activities, the essence of a timeless Fourth of July home celebration lies in spending quality time with friends and family, celebrating patriotism, and appreciating the freedom and values that make the United States unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is currently looking for work or is looking for hiring assistance, RX2 Solutions is here to help. Feel free to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt; or 610.340.3490 to discuss how we can be of service to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Timeless Fourth of July Home Celebrations The Fourth of July is a time-honored holiday in the United States, and while public gatherings and events are fantastic, celebrating the 4th at home with friends and family can be just as memorable and eventful! Here are five timeless Fourth of July home celebrations that you can enjoy with your family and friends at home:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unveiling the Top Interview Questions from a Hiring Manager’s Perspective</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/Unveiling-the-Top-Interview-Questions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unveiling the Top Interview Questions from a Hiring Manager&apos;s Perspective" /><published>2023-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/Unveiling%20the%20Top%20Interview%20Questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/28/Unveiling-the-Top-Interview-Questions.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unveiling the Top Interview Questions from a Hiring Manager’s Perspective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a hiring manager, conducting interviews is crucial in finding the right candidate. It is essential to ask the right questions to understand candidates better and assess their suitability for the role. This article aims to shed light on the top interview questions from the perspective of a hiring manager, enabling you to evaluate potential candidates effectively. &lt;!--more--&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can you walk me through your experience and qualifications related to this role? This question is a starting point, allowing candidates to showcase their relevant skills, experience, and qualifications. It helps you assess their suitability for the position and provides insight into their understanding of the role’s requirements. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you approach problem-solving and handling challenging situations? Solving problems and navigating challenging situations is crucial for success in any role. This question helps gauge a candidate’s problem-solving skills, approach to overcoming obstacles, and ability to think critically under pressure. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can you provide examples of your previous work demonstrating your skills and abilities relevant to this position? By asking for concrete examples, you can gain insight into a candidate’s past accomplishments and application of relevant skills related to the role. This question allows candidates to showcase their expertise and provides tangible evidence of their capabilities. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What do you know about our company, and why are you interested in working here? Candidates who have researched your company demonstrate genuine interest and enthusiasm. Their response allows you to assess their level of preparation, understanding of your organization’s values, and alignment with the company’s mission and culture. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you handle working under pressure and tight deadlines? The ability to perform effectively under pressure is essential in many roles. This question provides insights into a candidate’s resilience, time management skills, and ability to prioritize tasks when faced with challenging deadlines. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can you tell me about a time when you had to work collaboratively with a team to achieve a common goal? Teamwork is often a vital aspect of any role. By asking for examples of past collaboration, you can evaluate a candidate’s interpersonal skills, communication abilities, and ability to contribute effectively to a team’s success. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What steps do you take to stay updated and informed about industry trends and developments? This question allows you to assess a candidate’s passion for continuous learning and their proactive approach to staying informed in their field. Their response provides insight into their commitment to professional growth and ability to adapt to evolving industry trends. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can you share an example of a time when you had to adapt to change or overcome a significant obstacle in the workplace? Change is inevitable in any organization, and adaptability is a valuable trait. This question helps you gauge a candidate’s flexibility, problem-solving abilities in challenging situations, and resilience when facing unexpected obstacles. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How do you prioritize and manage your workload effectively? Time management and prioritization skills are crucial for productivity and success. This question allows you to evaluate a candidate’s organizational skills, their ability to manage multiple tasks, and their focus on achieving objectives within given timeframes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Can you provide an example of a project or accomplishment you are particularly proud of, and explain your role in it? Asking candidates to highlight a specific achievement allows them to showcase their accomplishments and impact. Their response will enable you to assess their level of initiative, problem-solving abilities, and potential contribution to your organization. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviews as a hiring manager involve asking thought-provoking questions that provide insights into candidates’ qualifications, skills and fit within your organization. The ten interview questions discussed above provide a solid foundation for evaluating candidates and making informed hiring decisions. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is currently looking for work or is looking for hiring assistance, RX2 Solutions is here to help. Feel free to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt; or 610.340.3490 to discuss how we can be of service to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Unveiling the Top Interview Questions from a Hiring Manager’s Perspective As a hiring manager, conducting interviews is crucial in finding the right candidate. It is essential to ask the right questions to understand candidates better and assess their suitability for the role. This article aims to shed light on the top interview questions from the perspective of a hiring manager, enabling you to evaluate potential candidates effectively.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fourth of July Activities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/27/4th-of-July-Activities.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fourth of July Activities" /><published>2023-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/27/4th%20of%20July%20Activities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/27/4th-of-July-Activities.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again when everyone is looking for Fun Family activities for the Fourth of July. Well, look no further, as RX2 Solutions 
has highlighted some of the best events in the area!
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOURTH OF JULY ACTIVITIES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pennsylvania&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Philadelphia, Wawa Welcome America July 4th Concert&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, July 4, 2023 | 7 p.m. Time of Fireworks: 9:45 p.m&lt;br /&gt;
This is it: the big one. Wawa Welcome America culminates in a giant, free-for-everyone party on the Benjamin Franklin Parkway on the evening of the Fourth of July. The centerpiece of the celebration is a high-energy concert headlined by superstars Ludacris and Demi Lovato ahead of a stunning fireworks finale. Note: Guests can enter the Parkway through gates at 20th Street and Logan Circle beginning at 4 p.m.&lt;br /&gt;
Where: Benjamin Franklin Parkway, 200 N. 19th Street &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Penn’s Landing, Pershing’s Own Concert, and Waterfront Fireworks&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Saturday, July 1, 2023 | 8-9:45 p.m.&lt;br /&gt;
Originally formed back in 1922 by General John J. Pershing, the United States Army band Pershing’s Own comes to Philadelphia for a patriotic, star-spangled concert — capped off by an exciting fireworks show over the water. (And Philly has no shortage of spots to enjoy the fireworks.)&lt;br /&gt;
Where: Great Plaza at Penn’s Landing, 101 S. Christopher Columbus Boulevard &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wayne, Wilson Farm Park Fourth of July Celebration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, July 4, 2023 | 7:15-9:15 p.m.&lt;br /&gt;
The Chester County Concert Band treats the town to patriotic tunes while folks gather in Wayne’s Wilson Farm Park ahead of an Independence Day fireworks display, lighting up the skies at dusk. This year, grab refreshments at one of the pay-as-you-go food and ice cream trucks or pack your own lawn chairs and picnics.&lt;br /&gt;
Where: Wilson Farm Park, 500 Lee Road, Wayne &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conshohocken, Sutcliffe Park&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Monday, July 3, 2023 | 9:30 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
The Borough of Conshohocken will host the Fireworks Display on Monday, July 3, 2023. Fireworks begin at dusk approximately around 9:30 p.m. The fireworks display will be larger so that fireworks may be visible from as many vantage points as possible throughout the Borough. Due to the larger size of fireworks, a wider safety perimeter surrounding the discharge zone is required. As such, Sutcliffe Park and surrounding areas will be closed to the public during the event. Tests of the larger Fireworks display were completed to ensure that the majority of the Borough could still view and enjoy the fireworks from outside Sutcliffe Park.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Allentown, J. Birney Crum Stadium&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
July 4, 2023 | 5 p.m. – 10 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
The City of Allentown’s free 4th of July Celebration is at J. Birney Crum Stadium on July 4 from 5–10 p.m. The event features live music and entertainment, family fun, delicious food options and a rousing, musical fireworks show. The stadium gates open at 5 p.m. The night will be capped by a brilliant fireworks display that is sure to dazzle the audience. The fireworks show will be accompanied by music broadcast throughout the stadium. More details on music performances to come.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jersey Shore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atlantic City Fireworks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Friday, June 30, 2023 | 9:30 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
North Beach Atlantic City has announced that the entertainment district of Atlantic City will host its 3rd annual summer-kick off premiere ocean-front firework spectacular on Friday, June 30, at 9:30 p.m. This event will be free and open to the public featuring several viewing locations throughout the north end of the boardwalk. The locations include: Steel Pier, Resorts Casino Hotel, Hard Rock Hotel &amp;amp; Casino Atlantic City, Showboat, and Ocean Casino Resort. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wildwood 4th of July Fireworks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, July 4, 2023 | 10 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
Celebrate Independence Day on the Wildwoods Boardwalk and enjoy the 4th of July Fireworks Spectacular at 10 p.m.! This special fireworks spectacular, launched from the beach at Pine Avenue, is synchronized to patriotic music playing over the Wildwoods Boardwalk sound system! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ocean City 4th of July Celebration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, July 4, 2023 | 7 p.m. – 9:30 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
Celebrate Independence Day down the shore in Ocean City with a kite flying competition at 7 pm, followed by live entertainment and a boardwalk fireworks display at 9 pm. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delaware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wilmington, Tubman-Garrett Riverfront Park&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, July 4, 2023 | 4 p.m. – 10 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
4:00 p.m. to 10:00 p.m. (fireworks preshow at 9:15) Tubman-Garrett Riverfront Park, Rosa Parks Drive, Wilmington, DE 19801 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dewey Beach 4th of July Fireworks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, July 4, 2023 | 9:30 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
Fireworks will once again light up the sky in Dewey Beach July 4. The display will launch from a barge in the bay in front of Northbeach/ Ivy, two blocks from the Rusty Rudder, and will be visible throughout town. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rehoboth Beach Firework Show&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Sunday, July 2, 2023 | 9:30 p.m. &lt;br /&gt;
Rehoboth Beach’s fireworks show will take place on Sunday, July 2 at 9:30 p.m. They say the display will be 20 minutes and visible along the beach and boardwalk. The Funsters will perform at the bandstand starting at 8 p.m. and will continue after the fireworks display. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know is currently looking for work or is looking for hiring assistance, RX2 Solutions is here to help. Feel free to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt; or 610.340.3490 to discuss how we can be of service to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">It’s that time of year again when everyone is looking for Fun Family activities for the Fourth of July. Well, look no further, as RX2 Solutions has highlighted some of the best events in the area!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Q3 2023 Hiring &amp;amp; Economic Outlook</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/27/Q3-2023-Hiring-&-Economic-Outlook.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Q3 2023 Hiring &amp; Economic Outlook" /><published>2023-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/06/27/Q3%202023%20Hiring%20&amp;%20Economic%20Outlook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/06/27/Q3-2023-Hiring-&amp;-Economic-Outlook.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Q3 2023 Hiring &amp;amp; Economic Outlook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite what many news stations are reporting, the US economy is doing well, and we are still seeing strong demand 
for staffing services.  Demand has gone down some from where it was in Q1 and Q2, and historically, we have 
experienced a slowdown during the summer months.  &lt;!--more--&gt; This year, some of our clients are experiencing temporary 
hiring freezes in some departments as they wait and see what the economy will do, and fortunately, the 
outlook is positive. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We keep hearing about a pending recession, and some believe it’s already started.  With a number of high profile 
companies announcing layoffs this year in &lt;strong&gt;Entertainment&lt;/strong&gt; (Disney/ESPN, Paramount, Showtime/MTV), 
&lt;strong&gt;Tech&lt;/strong&gt; (Microsoft/LinkedIn, Oracle, Meta), and &lt;strong&gt;Financial Services&lt;/strong&gt; (JPMC, USAA, Morgan Stanley) many people believe 
that the economy is doing poorly&lt;sup&gt;i&lt;/sup&gt;.  It’s our opinion that the majority of these layoffs are due to a correction 
from over-hiring during COVID or from the consequences of making poor strategic decisions rather than from broader 
economic issues.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One factor that is worse than it was before the pandemic is inflation.  To combat this, the Federal Reserve has 
increased interest rates from .25% to 5.25% from March 2022 until today&lt;sup&gt;ii&lt;/sup&gt;.  One of the consequences of the 
interest rate hikes and inflation is that US Savings Bonds have gone down in value leading the failure of 
Silicon Valley Bank and speculation of the overall economic health of the Country&lt;sup&gt;iii&lt;/sup&gt;.  Increasing interest rates 
appears to be having the desired effect and inflation is down from over 9% in June 2022 to just over 4% today&lt;sup&gt;iv&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
The target inflation rate is 2% so there is still work to be done and the Fed has indicated that they will likely 
raise rates further this year which may have an impact on the demand for labor&lt;sup&gt;v&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Unemployment, the measure of how many people are actively looking for work vs how many are working, reached a 20+ 
year low of 3.4% in April 2023 and is doing better than pre-pandemic levels&lt;sup&gt;vi&lt;/sup&gt;.  The US unexpectedly added 339,000 
jobs in May 2023, sending the stock market higher in June&lt;sup&gt;vii&lt;/sup&gt;.  One factor that is worse than it was before the pandemic 
is the labor participation rate – this is the measure of how many non-incarcerated people between the ages of 
18-65 are working.  This rate was 63.4% in February 2020, hit a low of 60.8% in May 2020 and has slowly risen to 
62.6% where it stands today.  This represents that around seven million people who were working before the pandemic 
have not returned to the workforce yet&lt;sup&gt;viii&lt;/sup&gt;.  There are a number of reasons why economists believe people have not 
returned to work including desire for higher wages reducing interest in low-paying jobs, aging baby boomers taking 
early retirement, increased dependent care needs, and a possible increase in people being paid under the table&lt;sup&gt;ix&lt;/sup&gt;. With unemployment rates being historically low and seven million people leaving the workforce that have not returned yet since 2020, it’s unlikely that we will see a dramatic shift in the labor supply in the near-term.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
On the demand side, there are a historic number of advertised job vacancies in the US currently. Across all regions 
and industries there were 10.1 million job postings as of April 2023&lt;sup&gt;x&lt;/sup&gt;.  Over the past 25 years, there were never more 
than 8 million postings (until mid-2021), and the historical average is around five million.  Economists were 
surprised by the April numbers as the number of postings declined for three straight months from a near-historical 
high of 11.2 million in December 2022 and then spiked in April.  This data is good news for employees and not 
necessarily the best news for employers as the demand for labor is high and the supply is low.  This trend will 
likely lead to further increases in wages for employers to remain competitive in the marketplace and attract the 
talent they need.  Some areas we’ve identified where employers can improve their hiring success is to increase 
their perceived employee benefits and to streamline and expedite their interview process.  If you’d like to 
discuss your hiring strategy with RX2 Solutions and how we can play a part in it, feel free to reach 
out to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt;, 610.340.3490. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;be&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
____________________________ &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;i&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/brianbushard/2023/06/26/2023-layoff-tracker-goldman-sachs-reportedly-cutting-managing-directors/?sh=10059a376b90&quot;&gt;www.forbes.com/brianbushard&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;ii&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/advisor/investing/fed-funds-rate-history&quot;&gt;www.forbes.com/inesting&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;iii&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techtarget.com/whatis/feature/Silicon-Valley-Bank-collapse-explained-What-you-need-to-know#:~:text=The%20collapse%20happened%20for%20multiple,SVB&apos;s%20depositors%20were%20startup%20companies&quot;&gt;www.techtarget.com/Silicon-Valley-Bank-collapse&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;iv&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ycharts.com/indicators/us_inflation_rate&quot;&gt;www.ycharts.com/indicators/us&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;v&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cfr.org/blog/history-and-future-federal-reserves-2-percent-target-rate-inflation-0#:~:text=The%202%20percent%20target%20was,of%20then%2D%20Chair%20Ben%20Bernanke.&amp;amp;text=Despite%20coming%20about%20somewhat%20accidentally,is%20a%20reasonable%20inflation%20target&quot;&gt;www.cfr.org&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;vi&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bls.gov/charts/employment-situation/civilian-unemployment-rate.htm&quot;&gt;www.bls.gov/charts/employment&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;vii&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2023/06/02/jobs-report-may-2023-.html&quot;&gt;www.cnbc.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;viii&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ycharts.com/indicators/labor_force_participation_rate#:~:text=Basic%20Info,long%20term%20average%20of%2062.84%25&quot;&gt;www.ycharts.com/labor_force&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;ix&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/qai/2023/01/25/unemployment-is-low-but-so-is-the-labor-force-participation-rate---whats-going-on-in-the-us-labor-market/?sh=10f98c3e244e&quot;&gt;www.forbes.com/unemployment&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;x&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradingeconomics.com/united-states/job-offers#:~:text=Openings%20Unexpectedly%20Rise-,The%20number%20of%20job%20vacancies%20in%20the%20United%20States%20unexpectedly,market%20expectations%20of%209.375%20million&quot;&gt;www.tradingeconomics.com/united-states/job&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/be&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">RX2 Solutions Q3 2023 Hiring &amp;amp; Economic Outlook Despite what many news stations are reporting, the US economy is doing well, and we are still seeing strong demand for staffing services. Demand has gone down some from where it was in Q1 and Q2, and historically, we have experienced a slowdown during the summer months.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Welcomes Jeff Carroll as their Director of Sales</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/31/Welcome-Jeff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Welcomes Jeff Carroll as their Director of Sales" /><published>2023-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/05/31/Welcome%20Jeff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/05/31/Welcome-Jeff.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RX2 Solutions
610.340.3490
info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Welcomes Jeff Carroll as their Director of Sales&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Newtown Square, PA, May 31st, 2023&lt;/em&gt;] RX2 Solutions, The Respectfully Professional Talent Acquisition and Staff Augmentation Company is proud to announce the arrival of its Director of Sales, Jeff Carroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/JCBW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amanda Headshot&quot; /&gt;
Jeff Carroll brings over 20 years of client management and business development experience in Technology Staffing and Solutions. He employs a consultative approach with his clients, fostering long-term relationships which aligns well with the RX2 Solutions culture and Respectfully Professional Process.
His flexible approach allows ease of use for all his clients and he’s excited to bring his knowledge and experience to the RX2 family. Jeff grew up in the Philly suburbs and graduated from Ursinus College with a bachelor’s degree in marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of work, Jeff enjoys spending time with his wife and 2 daughters playing golf, working out, and enjoying craft beer, scotch, and bourbon. And, of course, all things Philly sports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am extremely excited to join the RX2 Family.  I look forward to working with the team to help them succeed and grow the client base and business.  They have a great culture, team, and client base.  As a team we can take RX2 to the next level.”  When asked why he chose RX2, “I have known Rob for about a decade and he has always been one of the best in the business.  And I have competed against Ross for over a decade as well.  It only made sense to combine forces and take RX2 to the next level.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RX2 Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt;
RX2 Solutions was founded on the principle of being a Respectfully Professional Company. We have evolved from a Staffing firm into a Technology Company that delivers customized Staff Augmentation and Talent Acquisition Solutions in the areas of Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Creative &amp;amp; Marketing, Engineering &amp;amp; Supply Chain, Information Technology, and Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical.  Our differentiator is our Respectfully Professional Process, which has been derived from three decades of successful industry experience focusing on delivering solution-based talent acquisition and staffing strategies. The result is consultative approach, enjoyable experience, and professional result.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Welcomes Brandon Caruso as their Recruiting Manager</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/15/Welcome-Brandon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Welcomes Brandon Caruso as their Recruiting Manager" /><published>2021-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/15/Welcome%20Brandon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/15/Welcome-Brandon.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RX2 Solutions
610.340.3490
info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Welcomes Brandon Caruso as their Recruiting Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Plymouth Meeting, PA, July 15th, 2021&lt;/em&gt;] RX2 Solutions, The Respectfully Professional Talent Acquisition and Staff Augmentation Company is proud to announce the arrival of its newest Recruiting Manager, Brandon Caruso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/BC150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amanda Headshot&quot; /&gt;
Brandon Caruso brings 7 years of diverse staffing experience as both a top producing Recruiter, and as the Manager of a technical staffing team that provides tailored candidate searches. He received his Bachelor’s Degree in Economics and Political Science from the University of Pittsburgh. Brandon is a firm believer in providing a quality over quantity staffing approach that resonates well with RX2’s Respectfully Professional Process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his spare time Brandon enjoys riding his motorcycle, mountain biking, snowboarding, spending time outdoors, and working on DIY projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We knew from the moment we met Brandon that he would be an excellent fit for our organization and that he would genuinely embody our Respectfully Professional Process,” said Graham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RX2 Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt;
RX2 Solutions was founded on the principle of being a Respectfully Professional Company. We have evolved from a Staffing firm into a Technology Company that delivers customized Staff Augmentation and Talent Acquisition Solutions in the areas of Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Creative &amp;amp; Marketing, Engineering &amp;amp; Supply Chain, Information Technology, and Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical.  Our differentiator is our Respectfully Professional Process, which has been derived from three decades of successful industry experience focusing on delivering solution-based talent acquisition and staffing strategies. The result is consultative approach, enjoyable experience, and professional result.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</summary></entry></feed>