<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-01T10:08:49-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">RX2Solutions.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Welcomes John Thomas as an Associate, Strategic Staffing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/21/Welcome-John.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Welcomes John Thomas as an Associate, Strategic Staffing" /><published>2021-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/21/Welcome%20John</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/21/Welcome-John.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RX2 Solutions
610.340.3490
info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Welcomes John Thomas as an Associate, Strategic Staffing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Plymouth Meeting, PA, April 21th, 2021&lt;/em&gt;] RX2 Solutions, The Respectfully Professional Talent Acquisition and Staff Augmentation Company is proud to announce the arrival of its newest Associate, Strategic Staffing John Thomas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/JBT B-W HEADSHOT RX2-150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;John Headshot&quot; /&gt;
John comes from a nationally recognized home health care company and has a strong background in customer service, vendor management, and IT support.  Originally from the suburbs of Philadelphia, he received his degree in Health Policy and Administration from Penn State University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is a lifelong Phillies and Eagles fan who enjoys traveling, exploring the outdoors, spending time with friends and family, and playing his guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“John has the personality, customer service skills and likability factor that our clients have come to expect.”, said Ross Rosner Managing Partner of RX2 Solutions.  “As our organization continues to grow, we see John playing a key role. ”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RX2 Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt;
RX2 Solutions was founded on the principle of being a Respectfully Professional Company. We have evolved from a Staffing firm into a Technology Company that delivers customized Staff Augmentation and Talent Acquisition Solutions in the areas of Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Creative &amp;amp; Marketing, Engineering &amp;amp; Supply Chain, Information Technology, and Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical.  Our differentiator is our Respectfully Professional Process, which has been derived from three decades of successful industry experience focusing on delivering solution-based talent acquisition and staffing strategies. The result is consultative approach, enjoyable experience, and professional result.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Welcomes Amanda Narcise as their Recruiting Manager</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/08/Welcome-Amanda.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Welcomes Amanda Narcise as their Recruiting Manager" /><published>2021-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/03/08/Welcome%20Amanda</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/08/Welcome-Amanda.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RX2 Solutions
610.340.3490
info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Welcomes Amanda Narcise as their Recruiting Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Plymouth Meeting, PA, March 8th, 2021&lt;/em&gt;] RX2 Solutions, The Respectfully Professional Talent Acquisition and Staff Augmentation Company is proud to announce the arrival of its newest Recruiting Manager, Amanda Narcise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/AN150_BW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amanda Headshot&quot; /&gt;
Amanda Narcise brings over 10 years of professional staffing experience in the life science, healthcare, and administrative space to RX2 Solutions. She is a go-getter who is energized by results and was drawn to the professional environment, similar mindset, and Respectfully Professional culture of RX2 Solutions. She has a tenacious drive for creating staffing solutions that exceed business goals while providing the highest level of service to the client and the job seeker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda enjoys spending time with her nieces and nephew in her spare time, going down the shore and trying out new restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are ecstatic to have Amanda on our team, and we knew from the very first meeting she would play a crucial role in growing our organization”, said Graham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RX2 Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt;
RX2 Solutions was founded on the principle of being a Respectfully Professional Company. We have evolved from a Staffing firm into a Technology Company that delivers customized Staff Augmentation and Talent Acquisition Solutions in the areas of Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Creative &amp;amp; Marketing, Engineering &amp;amp; Supply Chain, Information Technology, and Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical.  Our differentiator is our Respectfully Professional Process, which has been derived from three decades of successful industry experience focusing on delivering solution-based talent acquisition and staffing strategies. The result is consultative approach, enjoyable experience, and professional result.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I have the perfect resume, Now what?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/19/perfect-resume.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I have the perfect resume, Now what?" /><published>2021-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/19/perfect-resume</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/19/perfect-resume.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have the perfect resume, now what?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have perfected your resume, it’s time to put yourself out there and apply to various roles of interest.  In case you missed them, please check out our articles about resume writing best practices and resume formatting.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are actively looking for a job, you may need to change some of your habits…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make it easy for potential employers to contact you.&lt;/strong&gt;
This means that you make sure your phone settings and email settings allow people who aren’t your “contacts” to get through.  Many companies are moving towards texting candidates to set up interviews with RX2 Solutions being one of them.  I know that sometimes you receive SPAM text messages and want to block everyone you don’t know – however if you do this across the board, you’ll never see the text about your resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Our Advice:&lt;/strong&gt; while you are looking for work, bite the bullet and loosen up your SPAM/SCAM blocking tools on your phone and email so people can get through to you.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When someone calls you, pick up the phone.&lt;/strong&gt;
The tendency these days is to screen all calls where you don’t know the number.  If you do this, you may be screening out someone who you actually want to speak with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Our Advice:&lt;/strong&gt;  When looking for work, STOP screening your calls!  We know it’s a hard habit to break – when an unknown number comes through its probably the auto warranty scam or some other scam call.  When you are looking for work, pick up your phone – you never know when someone will be calling you about a job that may or may not still be available when you get around to calling them back.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a professional voicemail&lt;/strong&gt;
This is especially true for recent college grads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Our Advice:&lt;/strong&gt;  Make sure your voicemail is professional as an unprofessional voicemail may lead to you never getting the interview and you’d never know it.  If you are unsure about what your voicemail should be, you can find some ideas &lt;a href=&quot;https://corporatefinanceinstitute.com/resources/careers/soft-skills/professional-voicemail-greetings/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only apply for jobs that you are a 75%+ fit for.&lt;/strong&gt;
Some candidates think that the more jobs they apply to, the better the chance is of getting a job.  I’ve also heard that some candidates apply to one job hoping that they can talk to you about something else.  This is a poor strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is actually happens when you apply for a bunch of roles that you aren’t a fit for, the employer will block you from applying to ALL jobs for a period of time OR indefinitely – including ones that you might be qualified for.  In the mind of an employer, applying to a number of roles that you aren’t a fit for is similar to “the boy who cried wolf”.  Once you are blocked, you won’t know it and most applicant tracking systems have a way to eliminate candidates for a certain period of time or indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Our Advice:&lt;/strong&gt;  Be selective with the roles you apply to.  Avoid the temptation of single click applying to multiple jobs that some job sites offer.  Tossing your resume at every job out there is a surefire way of unintentionally getting yourself banned/eliminated from a number of companies.
 &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As always if you are interested in career opportunities or doing business with us, please do not hestitate to reach out to us directly&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;610.340.3490&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:recruitment@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;recruitment@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">I have the perfect resume, now what? Once you have perfected your resume, it’s time to put yourself out there and apply to various roles of interest. In case you missed them, please check out our articles about resume writing best practices and resume formatting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interviewing 101</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/13/Interviewing-101.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interviewing 101" /><published>2020-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/13/Interviewing-101</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/13/Interviewing-101.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interviewing 101&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again, people are looked over, promotions are given to someone else, or it’s just time to make a change. Regardless of your reasons for looking at new opportunities, congratulations on getting your interview!  This guide covers the three phases of an interview: pre-interview, during interview and post-interview.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Interview&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research the company extensively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thoroughly review company’s website.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Look them up on LinkedIn and see what types of employees they have, where the employees are located, how long most employees have been with the company, etc. Maybe you’ll know someone who works there who could give you a referral.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Look up recent news stories about the company – you never know what you’ll find and how you can use it to position yourself positively during the                   interview.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thoroughly review your own resume!  If its on your resume, its fair game for the interviewer to ask you about it.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Our tips on resume writing can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rx2solutions.com/2020/08/19/resume-writing.html&quot;&gt;Resume Writing 101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One common mistake is that job seekers don’t fully update their resume and have items on the resume that they used freshman year of undergrad or                   something from a job 10+ years ago that they no longer use.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you are asked about something on your resume and you aren’t familiar with it, the interviewer automatically thinks “what else on here are you not               familiar with anymore”.  It’s the &lt;strong&gt;Van Halen Brown M&amp;amp;M theory&lt;/strong&gt; that you can read about here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/232420&quot;&gt;Van Halen Brown M&amp;amp;M theory&lt;/a&gt; and it takes the interview to a place that you don’t want it to go - usually eliminating you from consideration.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure you either update your resume to only the skills you have that are current OR go through a refresher to ensure you can competently discuss               everything.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During the Interview&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviewing in the post-COVID world can take many forms and video interviewing is more common than ever.  Below we will discuss best practices for any interview and then give specifics for phone, video, and on-site interviewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advice for all interviews&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before the day of the interview – make sure you know the logistics:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phone:  who is calling who – OR are you using a bridge line.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Video:  make sure you have the video meeting information.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In-person:  make sure you know where you are meeting, how to get there, what entrance to use, where to park, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Always tell the truth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If something can be said in a positive or a negative way, figure out how to say it in a positive way.  This means never talking negatively about former             employers or co-workers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most interviews are going to ask you some or all of the following questions, so rehearse positive ways to answer the following questions:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tell me about yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why are you looking for a new role?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why are you interested in this role / this company?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Explaining any resume gaps.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are plenty of resources online that describe common interview questions.  Below is an article that we suggest you review in detail.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com/advice/interview-questions-and-answers&quot;&gt;https://www.themuse.com/advice/interview-questions-and-answers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If at some point during the interview you are asked a question and you don’t know the answer – tell the truth!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hiring managers want honest employees who they can trust.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Getting caught fudging an answer that you aren’t 100% sure of is an easy way to get yourself eliminated from contention.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Avoid using the term “I’m a fast learner” or similar cliches.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the end of the interview, the interviewer is going to ask if you have any questions.  Many job seekers incorrectly think it’s a compliment to say              something like “You did a great job explaining things, thank you – I don’t have any questions.” Unfortunately, this isn’t a compliment and is a major              mistake.  The feedback we receive when a candidate asks no questions is “they didn’t seem engaged or interested in the role”.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure you ask 2-5 relevant questions for the interviewer that you aren’t able to find answers for from doing your own research.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;These questions should be based on “impact” and should be relevant to what’s important to you such as:  company culture, management style, company’s               expectations for the role, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrapping up the interview.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you are interested in the role, you can tell the interviewer that you are interested and that you hope to move to the next step in the interview             process.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never&lt;/strong&gt; ask the question “&lt;strong&gt;when can I start?&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phone Interview&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you are somewhere quiet, where you won’t be interrupted, with good phone reception.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you’re a great multi-tasker, make the interview your only task.  The most common mistake here is that job seekers take the phone interview while        driving, using Bluetooth.  We highly advise against this – the interview should be your only priority while it’s happening.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have a headset, use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video Interview&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrive at least 5 minutes early to the interview.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treat the video interview like an in-person interview in terms of what you wear.  If you would dress business formal for the on-site interview, that’s what     you should wear for the video interview.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice joining the video interview a day or two before the actual interview to ensure that your video equipment is working and that you are able to join.     The last thing you want is to find out there’s an issue 5-minutes before the interview when its too late to fix anything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you are somewhere quiet, with good lighting, strong internet connection and that the camera is pointed at you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With regards to setting, make sure there is as little clutter in the background as possible.  The attention during the interview should be on you rather        than on the room you are in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have a headset, headphones and an external microphone then use it.  Sometimes with video interviews, the sound quality can suffer, and you want to      be able to put your best foot forward during the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-Person Interview&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Logistics:  Map out your route to the interview and plan on arriving at least 30 minutes early to the general vicinity of the interview.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This does NOT mean arrive at the company’s building 30 minutes early as doing this would be a major mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What it DOES mean is that if you arrive early, find somewhere to go that’s close to the interview to wait such as a coffee shop, bookstore, restaurant, or      somebody else’s parking lot.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrive at the interview location between 5-10 minutes early.  Some managers we work with say that being too early is just as bad as being late as both show      a lack of respect for the interviewer’s time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What to wear:  unless you are told otherwise, default to wearing business formal attire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What to bring with you:  bring a pen/pencil, notepad, portfolio of work (if applicable) and five copies of your resume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviewing is a skill that you can improve on with time.  Like anything else, controlling the areas that you can control are crucial for putting your best foot forward for an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or anyone you know if currently looking for work or is looking for hiring assistance, RX2 Solutions is here to help.  Feel free to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt; to discuss how we can be of service to you.  For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rx2solutions.com&quot;&gt;www.rx2solutions.com&lt;/a&gt; or call us at 610.340.3490.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Interviewing 101 It’s that time of year again, people are looked over, promotions are given to someone else, or it’s just time to make a change. Regardless of your reasons for looking at new opportunities, congratulations on getting your interview! This guide covers the three phases of an interview: pre-interview, during interview and post-interview.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Resume Writing: Best Practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resume Writing: Best Practices" /><published>2020-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing.html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you are gainfully employed and looking for a better opportunity, a recent college grad, or someone who was laid off due to COVID after being at the same company for 10-years, having a strong resume will help you find the opportunity that you want.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a combined 40-years of professional experience helping job seekers find new opportunities, here are the RX2 Solutions principles for writing a strong resume:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the Three C’s of Resume Writing: Clean, Consistent, Concise.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clean: does the resume look appealing to the eye?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consistent: are your verb tenses and formatting consistent?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Concise: less is more!  Did you say what you needed to in as few words as possible?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The resume should be written using the following perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What’s in it for me (from the employer’s perspective)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Write the resume for the job that you WANT, not for the jobs that you’ve HAD&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s OK to have multiple versions of your resume if you are open to multiple types of opportunities
     3. Put the responsibilities with the biggest impact at the TOP of each opportunity – don’t make me fish through fluff to find the good stuff…tell me up front.
     3. Less is more. If you can say something in five words instead of ten, say it in five.  If you can combine two bullet points into one, then do it.  The fewer words and fewer pages of a resume, the better!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Words never to use in a resume:&lt;/strong&gt; I, We, Responsible (for).  This is your resume, so its assumed that everything in here is about you and that you were responsible for everything in the resume.  Saying these words is redundant and not necessary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The top of the resume should include:&lt;/strong&gt; your Full Name, City, State, and Zip Code you live in (not your full address), phone number and email address.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make the email address professional and easy. Ideally, it should be some version of your name and a simple number.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email Domain: For the email address, please choose either GMAIL, Yahoo, Hotmail, or your own personal website domain name.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For recent college grads – it may be OK to use your school email address but at some point (soon) you are going to want to move away from that to another email address that’s much more common and easy to remember/type.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills section:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m a fan of the skills section – but only to a point.  Everything in your resume (including the skills section) should be something that you worked with PROFESSIONALLY.  The content on here should be relevant.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Be concise. This isn’t your chance to list everything you’ve ever done. Keep this section relevant, detailed, and concise.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Technologies that are no longer used should not be in your resume for example: Lotus Notes, Windows 95,98,XP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Too many times, recent college grads put everything in here that they ever did including a class that they took their Freshman year that has nothing to do with the JOB THEY WANT. That stuff doesn’t enhance your resume and does more harm than good.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Everything on your resume is FAIR GAME during an interview. If you have it on your resume, you better know about it.  If its been a while and you don’t remember it as well as you should, then either refresh yourself on it OR take it out of the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m a big fan of including objectives in the resume.  It should tell your future employer what value you can bring and the type of job that you are looking for.  It should read like the headline of a newspaper.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Example: Network Engineer with fifteen years of proven experience working in medium to enterprise level environments who is looking to leverage a proven track record to bring value to an organization.  Coachable, goal-oriented team player who thrives with both minimal and detailed instructions to accomplish company driven objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right-sizing your Role Titles:&lt;/strong&gt; Your title should accurately describe what you did and doesn’t necessarily need to be the official title that the company gave you.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you were the CEO of a three person company and are now looking for a mid-level manager role – consider right-sizing. Yes, your official title may have been CEO, but you were really a sales rep and an operations manager – so change your title to that.  If your potential employer sees CEO on your resume, they most likely will think you are overqualified and skip you because “its too big of a step back”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Conversely, if you were a “staff accountant” but managed three direct reports and handled all of the responsibilities of the month end close – say that you were the Accounting Supervisor.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t use this section to lie, but right-sizing your title can go a long way to getting the job that you are qualified for and deserve.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resume Bullet Points:&lt;/strong&gt; under each role, you should have bullet points that say what you did.  I’ve seen resumes that just have blocks of text and this should be avoided.  Again, the MOST impactful thing you did in the role should be the first bullet point listed and then you should go on to the second most impactful, then third most impactful, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistency is Key:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start every bullet point with a past tense verb. Even if you are currently employed and currently performing the responsibility, use a past tense verb because you can’t go wrong with it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t start multiple bullet points in a row with the same verb – break it up a little by using synonyms from time to time so you aren’t saying the exact same thing over and over.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure you either end every bullet point with a PERIOD (.) or none of them with a period. Be consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For month/date make sure you are using all of the same formatting. Our suggestion is just to spell out the full month instead of abbreviating it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Each month should line up in the same place; we suggest using the far right side of the screen. Every bullet point should be indented the same amount and the font on the resume should be consistent throughout.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unless you are in the creative space, we highly recommend using only one color of ink in the resume and that color should be black.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section Order:&lt;/strong&gt; the order that you put your resume together in matters!
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The order and format we recommend is: Name and contact info, Objective, (Skills), Professional Experience, (Volunteer, Part-Time, Internship experience), Education and Certifications.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is not included: “References Available Upon Request” should not be present on a resume. It is assumed that you are willing to furnish references prior to an offer being extended.  Also, your age, marital status, a photo of you&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volunteer work, part-time work, and side hustles should go below PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE and should each have their own sections. Often times these “non-full time” roles overlap with other opportunities and if you put them in the same section as your full time work, it can be confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Education and Certifications should at the bottom of the resume – except if you are a recent college grad. If you recently graduated, this section should go above your part-time and internship experience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RX2 Solutions is here to help! If you’d like to discuss your career goals, background, and opportunities we may have for you, please email your resume to info@rx2solutions.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Whether you are gainfully employed and looking for a better opportunity, a recent college grad, or someone who was laid off due to COVID after being at the same company for 10-years, having a strong resume will help you find the opportunity that you want.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing" /><published>2020-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RX2 Solutions
610.340.3490
info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Plymouth Meeting, PA, May 20th, 2020&lt;/em&gt;] RX2 Solutions, The Respectfully Professional Talent Acquisition and Staff Augmentation Company is proud to announce the arrival of its newest Director, Josh Roby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/JR-Headshot-150x150.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Josh headshot&quot; /&gt;
Josh comes from a national recruiting firm where he focused on Food &amp;amp; Beverage / Manufacturing &amp;amp; Supply Chain and his efforts helped grow the department seven-fold in the ten years he was there.  He is a native Philadelphian who attended Archbishop John Carroll and graduated from Penn State with his Degree in Business Management.  Josh, along with his wife and son, lives in the suburbs of Philadelphia and he is an avid Sixers and Phillies fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have known Josh for a very long time, and I am excited we finally have an opportunity to work together. Josh brings over a decade of staffing, team building, and operations experience, and we look forward to applying that expertise to help grow our Information Technology, Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical Staffing Divisions”, said Graham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RX2 Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt;
RX2 Solutions was founded on the principle of being a Respectfully Professional Company. We have evolved from a Staffing firm into a Technology Company that delivers customized Staff Augmentation and Talent Acquisition Solutions in the areas of Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Creative &amp;amp; Marketing, Engineering &amp;amp; Supply Chain, Information Technology, and Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical.  Our differentiator is our Respectfully Professional Process, which has been derived from three decades of successful industry experience focusing on delivering solution-based talent acquisition and staffing strategies. The result is consultative approach, enjoyable experience, and professional result.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Negotiating Salary in Your Existing Role (Part 1 of 2)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Negotiating Salary in Your Existing Role (Part 1 of 2)" /><published>2020-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;deciding-to-negotiate&quot;&gt;Deciding to Negotiate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this sounds familiar: It’s the hottest job market in recent memory and your company is growing. Since unemployment is at 50-year lows, new members to your team are being brought in at a premium in order to attract top-level talent. Your 2-4% annual raise is being outpaced by the market leaving proven contributors who have already been in the trenches to feel alienated, underpaid and underappreciated. After thinking about the salary for weeks or months, it’s time to ask for a raise. So now what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;negotiation-prep-work&quot;&gt;Negotiation Prep Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never negotiate anything unless you are prepared to walk away. Before you go down the road of asking for a raise, you need to figure out what you’ll do if the conversation doesn’t go the way you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Walking” in this case doesn’t mean quitting on the spot or doing something irrational that forces your employer to fire you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Walking away&lt;/em&gt; here means that you are prepared to leave the company – on your terms. This means performing due diligence on your next role, naturally going through the hiring process elsewhere, putting in two weeks’ notice and avoiding burning bridges when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leverage in negotiation comes from figuring out the other side’s best alternative and making your best alternative seem as strong as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The employer’s best alternative is usually to give the work to someone else or to hire someone to replace you. Before starting the negotiation, take a hard look at what it would look like at your company if you weren’t there and try to figure out how much pain it will cause your company if you move on. If the answer is “not much” then it’s probably not the best time to ask for a raise…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your best alternative is finding another job; this could be another job that you have already secured an offer for or it can be based on the research you’ve done in regard to current market rates for people with a similar skill set. In either case, do your research before starting the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of your research, we recommend you &lt;strong&gt;work with a consultative recruiter such as RX2 Solutions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A good recruiter will be interested in forming a relationship with you and won’t care that you aren’t completely sure if you’re ready to make a move yet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For additional information about selecting the right recruiter for you, please see Why work with a Quality-First Recruiter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;scheduling-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Scheduling the Conversation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timing is everything. Find the appropriate time to have the conversation and make sure that the meeting is scheduled ahead of time. A good time to address the topic is during an annual or quarterly review. If your company doesn’t have regular reviews good timing might be after a big win or the completion of a successful project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;during-the-meeting&quot;&gt;During the Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come prepared. Prepare everything that you can ahead of time from rehearsing what you are going to say, doing your research, and controlling the things that you can control.  Clearly state your good reasons for asking for a raise. Keep the conversation focused on you and keep it positive. Come up with a business case or proposition as to why you deserve the raise and include successes that you’ve had (especially recent successes), performance compared to goal and highlighting the value that you bring to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid bad reasons. Bad reasons include discussing what others are making or doing, threatening to leave or quit, or steering the conversation away from facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly define the next steps. End the meeting by establishing a timeline for the next steps so that you can hold management accountable for a timeline for getting you an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get whatever is agreed to in writing. It doesn’t need to be as formal as a new employment contract (yet), but whatever is decided at the end of the meeting, it’s a best practice to write it down so everyone is on the same page. It can be as simple as an email to your manager recapping the conversation/next steps and asking them to confirm that everything in your email is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next-article&quot;&gt;Next Article&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2 of this article will focus on Negotiating Your Salary when looking for a new opportunity.  If you believe you are at the point where are ready to start actively or passively looking for a new role, feel free to reach out to RX2 Solutions and we would be happy to discuss with you further.  You can reach us via email at info@rx2solutions.com or 610.340.3490&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Deciding to Negotiate Maybe this sounds familiar: It’s the hottest job market in recent memory and your company is growing. Since unemployment is at 50-year lows, new members to your team are being brought in at a premium in order to attract top-level talent. Your 2-4% annual raise is being outpaced by the market leaving proven contributors who have already been in the trenches to feel alienated, underpaid and underappreciated. After thinking about the salary for weeks or months, it’s time to ask for a raise. So now what?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Winner of the 76ers Raffle is…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Winner of the 76ers Raffle is..." /><published>2020-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner.html">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dan Diegel for winning the RX2 Solutions 76ers Raffle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who entered and if you would like to enter for our upcoming Phillies and 76ers Raffles please email us at info@rx2solutions.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video playsinline=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;object-fit: cover; border: none;&quot; autoplay=&quot;true&quot; muted=&quot;true&quot; preload=&quot;auto&quot; controls=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;https://rx2solutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/22020-Sixers.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional information about RX2 Solutions please visit www.rx2solutions.com or give us a call at 610.340.3490.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">Congratulations to Dan Diegel for winning the RX2 Solutions 76ers Raffle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy Holidays</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/10/happy-holidays.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Holidays" /><published>2019-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/10/happy-holidays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/10/happy-holidays.html">&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here at RX2 Solutions we wanted to take a moment to thank everyone who has made 2019 the life changing year it has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are truly grateful for each and everyone of you, especially our lovely wives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~RX2 Solutions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">Here at RX2 Solutions we wanted to take a moment to thank everyone who has made 2019 the life changing year it has been.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/RX2-Holiday-Photo-1200x1600.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/RX2-Holiday-Photo-1200x1600.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Work with a Quality-First Recruiter?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/28/why-work-with-a-quailty-first-recruiter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Work with a Quality-First Recruiter?" /><published>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/28/why-work-with-a-quailty-first-recruiter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/28/why-work-with-a-quailty-first-recruiter.html">&lt;p&gt;Business is going well, and you and your team have more work than you can handle - or maybe a key member of your team received an offer they can’t refuse, and they just put in their notice that they are moving on. Either way, you’re looking to hire a full-time employee in the hottest candidate market in the past 60 years. A little background on today’s current market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to the US Bureau of Labor Statistics, unemployment across the board in the U.S. is 3.5% (https://data.bls.gov/). To put this in context, unemployment was around 10% during the great recession and “full-employment” is 4.6%.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full-employment is the percentage of people employed where wages start to inflate because demand for workers outpaces supply. Unemployment includes all industries and job types across full-time, part-time, and seasonal workers who are actively looking for work but are not working. Specific areas that require high amounts of skill, like the roles that RX2 Solutions specializes in filling, have significantly lower local/regional unemployment rates, estimated in the 0-2% range.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many RX2 Solutions customers reach out to us as a first step when they are looking to hire. They appreciate our consultative nature, Respectfully Professional values, and our Quality over Quantity recruiting approach. RX2 Solutions is a trusted partner with all our clients providing them a wide variety of staffing solutions – but why work with a Quality first organization? Maybe this sounds like your company, maybe it doesn’t:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some organizations believe - “why pay a headhunter to help fill the role if I can fill it on my own?” So, you create a job description, go to the job boards to post your job and wait for the resumes to flow in. Depending on the role you are hiring for, you may find your candidate and you may not. However with unemployment being so low – I’ve heard from numerous organizations who post their open jobs that they are often inundated with candidates who aren’t a fit and they spend hours sifting through unqualified candidates to try to find a diamond in the rough often leading to a big waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why not start with a trusted solution to hire in in this environment? RX2 Solutions has several proprietary methods to help identify your ideal candidate and here are some best practices to have the most success possible in your search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make time for a call or meeting with the recruiter and the direct hiring manager.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If everything goes through HR, HR should attend the meeting as well.&lt;/em&gt; Investing 15-30 minutes of a busy hiring manager’s time to discuss the ideal candidate will save time over the course of the search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streamline your interview process.&lt;/strong&gt; Provide timely and meaningful feedback. When interviewing, fit everyone that the candidate needs to meet into one or two on-site visits. An extended interview process is one of the largest turnoffs for a candidate - and significantly increases the chance of having competing offers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate with the candidate through their recruiter (this includes discussing salary).&lt;/strong&gt; Communication is key in life, when you are provided a candidate from RX2 Solutions, the salary expectations are discussed several times before you receive the resume and the expectation from the candidate is that a competitive offer will meet or exceed their salary number. Allow us to help you; we know your interview process, how your organization likes to make offers, and what else a candidate has going us because of this we’ll be able to streamline and simplify the interview-to-hire process at your organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop worrying about internal equity - make an offer based on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; The U.S. economy has been above “full employment” for 30+ months and counting, with some sectors being at full employment for significantly longer than that. This high demand and low supply market have caused wages across the board to increase higher than inflation. If most of your team was hired more than 30 months ago, chances are your “internal equity” is below or well below the market. If someone down the street is willing to pay your ideal candidate more, offer better benefits, more vacation time, higher bonus, etc. you need to meet or beat your competition to remain competitive and attract top level talent. Artificially pegging your offered compensation to internal equity will often cause you to lose out on the A-level player that will help take your company to the next level.
Partnering with a Quality-First Recruiter can and should be one of the most reward experience your company should have. You will fill your key positions in a tight employment market as well as saving your organization time and money from not having this person in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and if you or your organization needs assistance please do not hesitate to reach out to us at info@rx2solutions.com or 610.340.3490.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Business is going well, and you and your team have more work than you can handle - or maybe a key member of your team received an offer they can’t refuse, and they just put in their notice that they are moving on. Either way, you’re looking to hire a full-time employee in the hottest candidate market in the past 60 years. A little background on today’s current market:</summary></entry></feed>