<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-06T16:41:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">rx2solutions-com</title><entry><title type="html">Resume Writing: Best Practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resume Writing: Best Practices" /><published>2020-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing.html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you are gainfully employed and looking for a better opportunity, a recent college grad, or someone who was laid off due to COVID after being at the same company for 10-years, having a strong resume will help you find the opportunity that you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a combined 40-years of professional experience helping job seekers find new opportunities, here are the RX2 Solutions principles for writing a strong resume:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the Three C’s of Resume Writing: Clean, Consistent, Concise.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clean: does the resume look appealing to the eye?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consistent: are your verb tenses and formatting consistent?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Concise: less is more!  Did you say what you needed to in as few words as possible?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The resume should be written using the following perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What’s in it for me (from the employer’s perspective)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Write the resume for the job that you WANT, not for the jobs that you’ve HAD&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s OK to have multiple versions of your resume if you are open to multiple types of opportunities
     3. Put the responsibilities with the biggest impact at the TOP of each opportunity – don’t make me fish through fluff to find the good stuff…tell me up front.
     3. Less is more. If you can say something in five words instead of ten, say it in five.  If you can combine two bullet points into one, then do it.  The fewer words and fewer pages of a resume, the better!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Words never to use in a resume:&lt;/strong&gt; I, We, Responsible (for).  This is your resume, so its assumed that everything in here is about you and that you were responsible for everything in the resume.  Saying these words is redundant and not necessary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The top of the resume should include:&lt;/strong&gt; your Full Name, City, State, and Zip Code you live in (not your full address), phone number and email address.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make the email address professional and easy. Ideally, it should be some version of your name and a simple number.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email Domain: For the email address, please choose either GMAIL, Yahoo, Hotmail, or your own personal website domain name.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For recent college grads – it may be OK to use your school email address but at some point (soon) you are going to want to move away from that to another email address that’s much more common and easy to remember/type.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills section:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m a fan of the skills section – but only to a point.  Everything in your resume (including the skills section) should be something that you worked with PROFESSIONALLY.  The content on here should be relevant.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Be concise. This isn’t your chance to list everything you’ve ever done. Keep this section relevant, detailed, and concise.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Technologies that are no longer used should not be in your resume for example: Lotus Notes, Windows 95,98,XP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Too many times, recent college grads put everything in here that they ever did including a class that they took their Freshman year that has nothing to do with the JOB THEY WANT. That stuff doesn’t enhance your resume and does more harm than good.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Everything on your resume is FAIR GAME during an interview. If you have it on your resume, you better know about it.  If its been a while and you don’t remember it as well as you should, then either refresh yourself on it OR take it out of the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m a big fan of including objectives in the resume.  It should tell your future employer what value you can bring and the type of job that you are looking for.  It should read like the headline of a newspaper.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Example: Network Engineer with fifteen years of proven experience working in medium to enterprise level environments who is looking to leverage a proven track record to bring value to an organization.  Coachable, goal-oriented team player who thrives with both minimal and detailed instructions to accomplish company driven objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right-sizing your Role Titles:&lt;/strong&gt; Your title should accurately describe what you did and doesn’t necessarily need to be the official title that the company gave you.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you were the CEO of a three person company and are now looking for a mid-level manager role – consider right-sizing. Yes, your official title may have been CEO, but you were really a sales rep and an operations manager – so change your title to that.  If your potential employer sees CEO on your resume, they most likely will think you are overqualified and skip you because “its too big of a step back”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Conversely, if you were a “staff accountant” but managed three direct reports and handled all of the responsibilities of the month end close – say that you were the Accounting Supervisor.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t use this section to lie, but right-sizing your title can go a long way to getting the job that you are qualified for and deserve.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resume Bullet Points:&lt;/strong&gt; under each role, you should have bullet points that say what you did.  I’ve seen resumes that just have blocks of text and this should be avoided.  Again, the MOST impactful thing you did in the role should be the first bullet point listed and then you should go on to the second most impactful, then third most impactful, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistency is Key:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start every bullet point with a past tense verb. Even if you are currently employed and currently performing the responsibility, use a past tense verb because you can’t go wrong with it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t start multiple bullet points in a row with the same verb – break it up a little by using synonyms from time to time so you aren’t saying the exact same thing over and over.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure you either end every bullet point with a PERIOD (.) or none of them with a period. Be consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For month/date make sure you are using all of the same formatting. Our suggestion is just to spell out the full month instead of abbreviating it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Each month should line up in the same place; we suggest using the far right side of the screen. Every bullet point should be indented the same amount and the font on the resume should be consistent throughout.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unless you are in the creative space, we highly recommend using only one color of ink in the resume and that color should be black.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section Order:&lt;/strong&gt; the order that you put your resume together in matters!
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The order and format we recommend is: Name and contact info, Objective, (Skills), Professional Experience, (Volunteer, Part-Time, Internship experience), Education and Certifications.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is not included: “References Available Upon Request” should not be present on a resume. It is assumed that you are willing to furnish references prior to an offer being extended.  Also, your age, marital status, a photo of you&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volunteer work, part-time work, and side hustles should go below PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE and should each have their own sections. Often times these “non-full time” roles overlap with other opportunities and if you put them in the same section as your full time work, it can be confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Education and Certifications should at the bottom of the resume – except if you are a recent college grad. If you recently graduated, this section should go above your part-time and internship experience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RX2 Solutions is here to help! If you’d like to discuss your career goals, background, and opportunities we may have for you, please email your resume to info@rx2solutions.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Whether you are gainfully employed and looking for a better opportunity, a recent college grad, or someone who was laid off due to COVID after being at the same company for 10-years, having a strong resume will help you find the opportunity that you want.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing" /><published>2020-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RX2 Solutions
610.340.3490
info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Plymouth Meeting, PA, May 20th, 2020&lt;/em&gt;] RX2 Solutions, The Respectfully Professional Talent Acquisition and Staff Augmentation Company is proud to announce the arrival of its newest Director, Josh Roby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/JR-Headshot-150x150.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Josh headshot&quot; /&gt;!
Josh comes from a National recruiting firm where he focused on Food &amp;amp; Beverage, Manufacturing &amp;amp; Supply chain and his efforts helped grow the department seven-fold in the ten years he was there.  He is a native Philadelphian who attended Archbishop John Carroll and graduated from Penn State with his Degree in Business Management.  Josh, along with his wife and son, lives in the suburbs of Philadelphia and he is an avid Sixers and Phillies fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have known Josh for a very long time, and I am excited we finally have an opportunity to work together. Josh brings over a decade of staffing, team building, and operations experience, and we look forward to applying that expertise to help grow our Information Technology, Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical Staffing Divisions”, said Graham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RX2 Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt;
RX2 Solutions was founded on the principle of being Respectfully Professional and offering the highest level of customer services to both the customer and the job seeker. RX2 Solutions specializes in proving world-class highly personalized Talent Acquisition and Staffing Solutions in the areas of Information Technology, Scientific, Clinical, Accounting, and Finance. Our services include project-based staffing, contract, contract-to-hire, and direct hire. Our differentiator comes from roughly 25 years of successful industry experience, focusing on providing solution-based talent acquisition and staffing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><category term="press" /><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Negotiating Salary in Your Existing Role (Part 1 of 2)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Negotiating Salary in Your Existing Role (Part 1 of 2)" /><published>2020-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;deciding-to-negotiate&quot;&gt;Deciding to Negotiate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this sounds familiar: It’s the hottest job market in recent memory and your company is growing. Since unemployment is at 50-year lows, new members to your team are being brought in at a premium in order to attract top-level talent. Your 2-4% annual raise is being outpaced by the market leaving proven contributors who have already been in the trenches to feel alienated, underpaid and underappreciated. After thinking about the salary for weeks or months, it’s time to ask for a raise. So now what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;negotiation-prep-work&quot;&gt;Negotiation Prep Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never negotiate anything unless you are prepared to walk away. Before you go down the road of asking for a raise, you need to figure out what you’ll do if the conversation doesn’t go the way you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Walking” in this case doesn’t mean quitting on the spot or doing something irrational that forces your employer to fire you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Walking away&lt;/em&gt; here means that you are prepared to leave the company – on your terms. This means performing due diligence on your next role, naturally going through the hiring process elsewhere, putting in two weeks’ notice and avoiding burning bridges when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leverage in negotiation comes from figuring out the other side’s best alternative and making your best alternative seem as strong as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The employer’s best alternative is usually to give the work to someone else or to hire someone to replace you. Before starting the negotiation, take a hard look at what it would look like at your company if you weren’t there and try to figure out how much pain it will cause your company if you move on. If the answer is “not much” then it’s probably not the best time to ask for a raise…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your best alternative is finding another job; this could be another job that you have already secured an offer for or it can be based on the research you’ve done in regard to current market rates for people with a similar skill set. In either case, do your research before starting the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of your research, we recommend you &lt;strong&gt;work with a consultative recruiter such as RX2 Solutions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A good recruiter will be interested in forming a relationship with you and won’t care that you aren’t completely sure if you’re ready to make a move yet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For additional information about selecting the right recruiter for you, please see Why work with a Quality-First Recruiter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;scheduling-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Scheduling the Conversation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timing is everything. Find the appropriate time to have the conversation and make sure that the meeting is scheduled ahead of time. A good time to address the topic is during an annual or quarterly review. If your company doesn’t have regular reviews good timing might be after a big win or the completion of a successful project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;during-the-meeting&quot;&gt;During the Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come prepared. Prepare everything that you can ahead of time from rehearsing what you are going to say, doing your research, and controlling the things that you can control.  Clearly state your good reasons for asking for a raise. Keep the conversation focused on you and keep it positive. Come up with a business case or proposition as to why you deserve the raise and include successes that you’ve had (especially recent successes), performance compared to goal and highlighting the value that you bring to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid bad reasons. Bad reasons include discussing what others are making or doing, threatening to leave or quit, or steering the conversation away from facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly define the next steps. End the meeting by establishing a timeline for the next steps so that you can hold management accountable for a timeline for getting you an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get whatever is agreed to in writing. It doesn’t need to be as formal as a new employment contract (yet), but whatever is decided at the end of the meeting, it’s a best practice to write it down so everyone is on the same page. It can be as simple as an email to your manager recapping the conversation/next steps and asking them to confirm that everything in your email is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next-article&quot;&gt;Next Article&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2 of this article will focus on Negotiating Your Salary when looking for a new opportunity.  If you believe you are at the point where are ready to start actively or passively looking for a new role, feel free to reach out to RX2 Solutions and we would be happy to discuss with you further.  You can reach us via email at info@rx2solutions.com or 610.340.3490&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Deciding to Negotiate Maybe this sounds familiar: It’s the hottest job market in recent memory and your company is growing. Since unemployment is at 50-year lows, new members to your team are being brought in at a premium in order to attract top-level talent. Your 2-4% annual raise is being outpaced by the market leaving proven contributors who have already been in the trenches to feel alienated, underpaid and underappreciated. After thinking about the salary for weeks or months, it’s time to ask for a raise. So now what?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/accounting-343067_1280-cropped.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/accounting-343067_1280-cropped.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Winner of the 76ers Raffle is…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Winner of the 76ers Raffle is..." /><published>2020-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner.html">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dan Diegel for winning the RX2 Solutions 76ers Raffle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who entered and if you would like to enter for our upcoming Phillies and 76ers Raffles please email us at info@rx2solutions.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video playsinline=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;object-fit: cover; border: none;&quot; autoplay=&quot;true&quot; muted=&quot;true&quot; preload=&quot;auto&quot; controls=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;https://rx2solutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/22020-Sixers.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional information about RX2 Solutions please visit www.rx2solutions.com or give us a call at 610.340.3490.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">Congratulations to Dan Diegel for winning the RX2 Solutions 76ers Raffle.</summary></entry></feed>