<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-26T15:48:45-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">RX2Solutions.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">Resume Writing: Best Practices</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Resume Writing: Best Practices" /><published>2020-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/19/resume-writing.html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you are gainfully employed and looking for a better opportunity, a recent college grad, or someone who was laid off due to COVID after being at the same company for 10-years, having a strong resume will help you find the opportunity that you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a combined 40-years of professional experience helping job seekers find new opportunities, here are the RX2 Solutions principles for writing a strong resume:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the Three C’s of Resume Writing: Clean, Consistent, Concise.&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clean: does the resume look appealing to the eye?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Consistent: are your verb tenses and formatting consistent?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Concise: less is more!  Did you say what you needed to in as few words as possible?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The resume should be written using the following perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What’s in it for me (from the employer’s perspective)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Write the resume for the job that you WANT, not for the jobs that you’ve HAD&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s OK to have multiple versions of your resume if you are open to multiple types of opportunities
     3. Put the responsibilities with the biggest impact at the TOP of each opportunity – don’t make me fish through fluff to find the good stuff…tell me up front.
     3. Less is more. If you can say something in five words instead of ten, say it in five.  If you can combine two bullet points into one, then do it.  The fewer words and fewer pages of a resume, the better!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Words never to use in a resume:&lt;/strong&gt; I, We, Responsible (for).  This is your resume, so its assumed that everything in here is about you and that you were responsible for everything in the resume.  Saying these words is redundant and not necessary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The top of the resume should include:&lt;/strong&gt; your Full Name, City, State, and Zip Code you live in (not your full address), phone number and email address.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make the email address professional and easy. Ideally, it should be some version of your name and a simple number.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email Domain: For the email address, please choose either GMAIL, Yahoo, Hotmail, or your own personal website domain name.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For recent college grads – it may be OK to use your school email address but at some point (soon) you are going to want to move away from that to another email address that’s much more common and easy to remember/type.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills section:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m a fan of the skills section – but only to a point.  Everything in your resume (including the skills section) should be something that you worked with PROFESSIONALLY.  The content on here should be relevant.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Be concise. This isn’t your chance to list everything you’ve ever done. Keep this section relevant, detailed, and concise.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Technologies that are no longer used should not be in your resume for example: Lotus Notes, Windows 95,98,XP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Too many times, recent college grads put everything in here that they ever did including a class that they took their Freshman year that has nothing to do with the JOB THEY WANT. That stuff doesn’t enhance your resume and does more harm than good.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Everything on your resume is FAIR GAME during an interview. If you have it on your resume, you better know about it.  If its been a while and you don’t remember it as well as you should, then either refresh yourself on it OR take it out of the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m a big fan of including objectives in the resume.  It should tell your future employer what value you can bring and the type of job that you are looking for.  It should read like the headline of a newspaper.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Example: Network Engineer with fifteen years of proven experience working in medium to enterprise level environments who is looking to leverage a proven track record to bring value to an organization.  Coachable, goal-oriented team player who thrives with both minimal and detailed instructions to accomplish company driven objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right-sizing your Role Titles:&lt;/strong&gt; Your title should accurately describe what you did and doesn’t necessarily need to be the official title that the company gave you.
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you were the CEO of a three person company and are now looking for a mid-level manager role – consider right-sizing. Yes, your official title may have been CEO, but you were really a sales rep and an operations manager – so change your title to that.  If your potential employer sees CEO on your resume, they most likely will think you are overqualified and skip you because “its too big of a step back”.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Conversely, if you were a “staff accountant” but managed three direct reports and handled all of the responsibilities of the month end close – say that you were the Accounting Supervisor.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t use this section to lie, but right-sizing your title can go a long way to getting the job that you are qualified for and deserve.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resume Bullet Points:&lt;/strong&gt; under each role, you should have bullet points that say what you did.  I’ve seen resumes that just have blocks of text and this should be avoided.  Again, the MOST impactful thing you did in the role should be the first bullet point listed and then you should go on to the second most impactful, then third most impactful, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistency is Key:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start every bullet point with a past tense verb. Even if you are currently employed and currently performing the responsibility, use a past tense verb because you can’t go wrong with it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t start multiple bullet points in a row with the same verb – break it up a little by using synonyms from time to time so you aren’t saying the exact same thing over and over.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure you either end every bullet point with a PERIOD (.) or none of them with a period. Be consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For month/date make sure you are using all of the same formatting. Our suggestion is just to spell out the full month instead of abbreviating it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Each month should line up in the same place; we suggest using the far right side of the screen. Every bullet point should be indented the same amount and the font on the resume should be consistent throughout.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unless you are in the creative space, we highly recommend using only one color of ink in the resume and that color should be black.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Section Order:&lt;/strong&gt; the order that you put your resume together in matters!
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The order and format we recommend is: Name and contact info, Objective, (Skills), Professional Experience, (Volunteer, Part-Time, Internship experience), Education and Certifications.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is not included: “References Available Upon Request” should not be present on a resume. It is assumed that you are willing to furnish references prior to an offer being extended.  Also, your age, marital status, a photo of you&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Volunteer work, part-time work, and side hustles should go below PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE and should each have their own sections. Often times these “non-full time” roles overlap with other opportunities and if you put them in the same section as your full time work, it can be confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Education and Certifications should at the bottom of the resume – except if you are a recent college grad. If you recently graduated, this section should go above your part-time and internship experience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RX2 Solutions is here to help! If you’d like to discuss your career goals, background, and opportunities we may have for you, please email your resume to info@rx2solutions.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Whether you are gainfully employed and looking for a better opportunity, a recent college grad, or someone who was laid off due to COVID after being at the same company for 10-years, having a strong resume will help you find the opportunity that you want.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing" /><published>2020-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/20/rx2-welcomes-josh.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RX2 Solutions
610.340.3490
info@rx2solutions.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RX2 Solutions Welcomes Josh Roby as their Director, Strategic Staffing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;em&gt;Plymouth Meeting, PA, May 20th, 2020&lt;/em&gt;] RX2 Solutions, The Respectfully Professional Talent Acquisition and Staff Augmentation Company is proud to announce the arrival of its newest Director, Josh Roby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/JR-Headshot-150x150.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Josh headshot&quot; /&gt;
Josh comes from a National recruiting firm where he focused on Food &amp;amp; Beverage, Manufacturing &amp;amp; Supply chain and his efforts helped grow the department seven-fold in the ten years he was there.  He is a native Philadelphian who attended Archbishop John Carroll and graduated from Penn State with his Degree in Business Management.  Josh, along with his wife and son, lives in the suburbs of Philadelphia and he is an avid Sixers and Phillies fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have known Josh for a very long time, and I am excited we finally have an opportunity to work together. Josh brings over a decade of staffing, team building, and operations experience, and we look forward to applying that expertise to help grow our Information Technology, Accounting &amp;amp; Finance, Scientific &amp;amp; Clinical Staffing Divisions”, said Graham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About RX2 Solutions:&lt;/strong&gt;
RX2 Solutions was founded on the principle of being Respectfully Professional and offering the highest level of customer services to both the customer and the job seeker. RX2 Solutions specializes in proving world-class highly personalized Talent Acquisition and Staffing Solutions in the areas of Information Technology, Scientific, Clinical, Accounting, and Finance. Our services include project-based staffing, contract, contract-to-hire, and direct hire. Our differentiator comes from roughly 25 years of successful industry experience, focusing on providing solution-based talent acquisition and staffing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Negotiating Salary in Your Existing Role (Part 1 of 2)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Negotiating Salary in Your Existing Role (Part 1 of 2)" /><published>2020-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/03/06/negotiating-salary.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;deciding-to-negotiate&quot;&gt;Deciding to Negotiate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this sounds familiar: It’s the hottest job market in recent memory and your company is growing. Since unemployment is at 50-year lows, new members to your team are being brought in at a premium in order to attract top-level talent. Your 2-4% annual raise is being outpaced by the market leaving proven contributors who have already been in the trenches to feel alienated, underpaid and underappreciated. After thinking about the salary for weeks or months, it’s time to ask for a raise. So now what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;negotiation-prep-work&quot;&gt;Negotiation Prep Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never negotiate anything unless you are prepared to walk away. Before you go down the road of asking for a raise, you need to figure out what you’ll do if the conversation doesn’t go the way you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Walking” in this case doesn’t mean quitting on the spot or doing something irrational that forces your employer to fire you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Walking away&lt;/em&gt; here means that you are prepared to leave the company – on your terms. This means performing due diligence on your next role, naturally going through the hiring process elsewhere, putting in two weeks’ notice and avoiding burning bridges when possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leverage in negotiation comes from figuring out the other side’s best alternative and making your best alternative seem as strong as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The employer’s best alternative is usually to give the work to someone else or to hire someone to replace you. Before starting the negotiation, take a hard look at what it would look like at your company if you weren’t there and try to figure out how much pain it will cause your company if you move on. If the answer is “not much” then it’s probably not the best time to ask for a raise…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your best alternative is finding another job; this could be another job that you have already secured an offer for or it can be based on the research you’ve done in regard to current market rates for people with a similar skill set. In either case, do your research before starting the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of your research, we recommend you &lt;strong&gt;work with a consultative recruiter such as RX2 Solutions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A good recruiter will be interested in forming a relationship with you and won’t care that you aren’t completely sure if you’re ready to make a move yet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For additional information about selecting the right recruiter for you, please see Why work with a Quality-First Recruiter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;scheduling-the-conversation&quot;&gt;Scheduling the Conversation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timing is everything. Find the appropriate time to have the conversation and make sure that the meeting is scheduled ahead of time. A good time to address the topic is during an annual or quarterly review. If your company doesn’t have regular reviews good timing might be after a big win or the completion of a successful project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;during-the-meeting&quot;&gt;During the Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come prepared. Prepare everything that you can ahead of time from rehearsing what you are going to say, doing your research, and controlling the things that you can control.  Clearly state your good reasons for asking for a raise. Keep the conversation focused on you and keep it positive. Come up with a business case or proposition as to why you deserve the raise and include successes that you’ve had (especially recent successes), performance compared to goal and highlighting the value that you bring to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid bad reasons. Bad reasons include discussing what others are making or doing, threatening to leave or quit, or steering the conversation away from facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly define the next steps. End the meeting by establishing a timeline for the next steps so that you can hold management accountable for a timeline for getting you an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get whatever is agreed to in writing. It doesn’t need to be as formal as a new employment contract (yet), but whatever is decided at the end of the meeting, it’s a best practice to write it down so everyone is on the same page. It can be as simple as an email to your manager recapping the conversation/next steps and asking them to confirm that everything in your email is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;next-article&quot;&gt;Next Article&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2 of this article will focus on Negotiating Your Salary when looking for a new opportunity.  If you believe you are at the point where are ready to start actively or passively looking for a new role, feel free to reach out to RX2 Solutions and we would be happy to discuss with you further.  You can reach us via email at info@rx2solutions.com or 610.340.3490&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Deciding to Negotiate Maybe this sounds familiar: It’s the hottest job market in recent memory and your company is growing. Since unemployment is at 50-year lows, new members to your team are being brought in at a premium in order to attract top-level talent. Your 2-4% annual raise is being outpaced by the market leaving proven contributors who have already been in the trenches to feel alienated, underpaid and underappreciated. After thinking about the salary for weeks or months, it’s time to ask for a raise. So now what?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/accounting-343067_1280-cropped.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/accounting-343067_1280-cropped.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Winner of the 76ers Raffle is…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Winner of the 76ers Raffle is..." /><published>2020-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/22/76ers-raffle-winner.html">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dan Diegel for winning the RX2 Solutions 76ers Raffle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who entered and if you would like to enter for our upcoming Phillies and 76ers Raffles please email us at info@rx2solutions.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video playsinline=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;object-fit: cover; border: none;&quot; autoplay=&quot;true&quot; muted=&quot;true&quot; preload=&quot;auto&quot; controls=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;https://rx2solutions.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/22020-Sixers.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
  Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For additional information about RX2 Solutions please visit www.rx2solutions.com or give us a call at 610.340.3490.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">Congratulations to Dan Diegel for winning the RX2 Solutions 76ers Raffle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy Holidays</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/10/happy-holidays.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Holidays" /><published>2019-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/12/10/happy-holidays</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/12/10/happy-holidays.html">&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here at RX2 Solutions we wanted to take a moment to thank everyone who has made 2019 the life changing year it has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are truly grateful for each and everyone of you, especially our lovely wives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~RX2 Solutions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html">Here at RX2 Solutions we wanted to take a moment to thank everyone who has made 2019 the life changing year it has been.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/RX2-Holiday-Photo-1200x1600.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/RX2-Holiday-Photo-1200x1600.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Work with a Quality-First Recruiter?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/28/why-work-with-a-quailty-first-recruiter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Work with a Quality-First Recruiter?" /><published>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/28/why-work-with-a-quailty-first-recruiter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/28/why-work-with-a-quailty-first-recruiter.html">&lt;p&gt;Business is going well, and you and your team have more work than you can handle - or maybe a key member of your team received an offer they can’t refuse, and they just put in their notice that they are moving on. Either way, you’re looking to hire a full-time employee in the hottest candidate market in the past 60 years. A little background on today’s current market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;According to the US Bureau of Labor Statistics, unemployment across the board in the U.S. is 3.5% (https://data.bls.gov/). To put this in context, unemployment was around 10% during the great recession and “full-employment” is 4.6%.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full-employment is the percentage of people employed where wages start to inflate because demand for workers outpaces supply. Unemployment includes all industries and job types across full-time, part-time, and seasonal workers who are actively looking for work but are not working. Specific areas that require high amounts of skill, like the roles that RX2 Solutions specializes in filling, have significantly lower local/regional unemployment rates, estimated in the 0-2% range.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many RX2 Solutions customers reach out to us as a first step when they are looking to hire. They appreciate our consultative nature, Respectfully Professional values, and our Quality over Quantity recruiting approach. RX2 Solutions is a trusted partner with all our clients providing them a wide variety of staffing solutions – but why work with a Quality first organization? Maybe this sounds like your company, maybe it doesn’t:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some organizations believe - “why pay a headhunter to help fill the role if I can fill it on my own?” So, you create a job description, go to the job boards to post your job and wait for the resumes to flow in. Depending on the role you are hiring for, you may find your candidate and you may not. However with unemployment being so low – I’ve heard from numerous organizations who post their open jobs that they are often inundated with candidates who aren’t a fit and they spend hours sifting through unqualified candidates to try to find a diamond in the rough often leading to a big waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why not start with a trusted solution to hire in in this environment? RX2 Solutions has several proprietary methods to help identify your ideal candidate and here are some best practices to have the most success possible in your search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make time for a call or meeting with the recruiter and the direct hiring manager.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If everything goes through HR, HR should attend the meeting as well.&lt;/em&gt; Investing 15-30 minutes of a busy hiring manager’s time to discuss the ideal candidate will save time over the course of the search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streamline your interview process.&lt;/strong&gt; Provide timely and meaningful feedback. When interviewing, fit everyone that the candidate needs to meet into one or two on-site visits. An extended interview process is one of the largest turnoffs for a candidate - and significantly increases the chance of having competing offers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate with the candidate through their recruiter (this includes discussing salary).&lt;/strong&gt; Communication is key in life, when you are provided a candidate from RX2 Solutions, the salary expectations are discussed several times before you receive the resume and the expectation from the candidate is that a competitive offer will meet or exceed their salary number. Allow us to help you; we know your interview process, how your organization likes to make offers, and what else a candidate has going us because of this we’ll be able to streamline and simplify the interview-to-hire process at your organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop worrying about internal equity - make an offer based on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; The U.S. economy has been above “full employment” for 30+ months and counting, with some sectors being at full employment for significantly longer than that. This high demand and low supply market have caused wages across the board to increase higher than inflation. If most of your team was hired more than 30 months ago, chances are your “internal equity” is below or well below the market. If someone down the street is willing to pay your ideal candidate more, offer better benefits, more vacation time, higher bonus, etc. you need to meet or beat your competition to remain competitive and attract top level talent. Artificially pegging your offered compensation to internal equity will often cause you to lose out on the A-level player that will help take your company to the next level.
Partnering with a Quality-First Recruiter can and should be one of the most reward experience your company should have. You will fill your key positions in a tight employment market as well as saving your organization time and money from not having this person in place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and if you or your organization needs assistance please do not hesitate to reach out to us at info@rx2solutions.com or 610.340.3490.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Business is going well, and you and your team have more work than you can handle - or maybe a key member of your team received an offer they can’t refuse, and they just put in their notice that they are moving on. Either way, you’re looking to hire a full-time employee in the hottest candidate market in the past 60 years. A little background on today’s current market:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Top Candidates - September 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/18/top-candidates-september-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top Candidates - September 2019" /><published>2019-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/09/18/top-candidates-september-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/09/18/top-candidates-september-2019.html"></content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/Sept-2019-1-1200x1553.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/Sept-2019-1-1200x1553.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coaching Now; Generation Z and the Art of the Compromise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/07/coaching-now.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching Now; Generation Z and the Art of the Compromise" /><published>2019-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/07/coaching-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/07/coaching-now.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;preface&quot;&gt;Preface&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a manager and team leader, you’ve been very successful in your career and you know what has worked for you. In a given situation, you’ve seen the scenario play out two-dozen times and you know that your way works to approach a given situation. You are managing a group of Millennials and Gen Z who are approaching this problem for the first time and surprise, surprise - you aren’t seeing eye to eye with them. Maybe your way has been disrupted by new thinking or new technology. Maybe they don’t have the same experience that you do, and they simply cannot see why your way is the best or why it will work. In any event, for the team to execute effectively, you all need to be on the same page, but how do you get there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article will detail my experience coaching Millennials and Generation Z and the lessons I’ve learned that are transferrable to the business world. I believe that much of the material that has been written about the subject is general in nature and this article will provide specific situations from my experience along with what I learned at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up in the 1980’s and asked an adult a question that they didn’t want to answer, I often would be told “because I said so.” This answer left me frustrated and most of the time it meant the conversation was over. As the 1980s rolled into the 1990s and the early 2000s, I remember continuing to get the response from teachers, professors,coaches, and any number of other people in a position of authority - then at some point “because I told you so” just stopped. Sometime between the early-2000’s and now, it seemingly no longer became acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today, after retiring from a 20-year playing career, I am the third-year volunteer head coach of the Temple University Men’s Club Volleyball team. The players are all younger millennials and older members of Gen Z. I was born in 1981 making me an older millennial. Growing up I was told that sports are important because they teach life lessons. I find this to be true and believe that managing a sports team, a work team, or any group of people uses similar and transferrable skills. This article will detail what I have learned so far about successfully managing today’s young people through coaching a team sport and how these lessons can potentially be transferred to the business world and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;volleyball---the-ultimate-team-sport&quot;&gt;Volleyball - The Ultimate Team Sport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, Volleyball is the ultimate team sport. Unlike Basketball where one-star player can always handle the ball and take control of a game offensively or Baseball where a dominant pitcher can shut down another team’s offense, Volleyball (due to its rules) forces a team to work together to achieve a common goal. The basic rules are that each team can touch the ball three times before it goes over the net and if the ball hits the ground on your side, the other team gets a point. Typically, this leads to three different players contacting the ball on every possession and the other players on the court need to react and play their role based on the situation. It takes coordination and awareness to do correctly and if one player is out of position or makes a mistake, the rest of the team suffers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recent-history-of-the-team&quot;&gt;Recent History of the Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been involved with the team for the past four years - split between being a player and then later, as coach. Before I became the coach, the position had been vacant for the better part of two decades. My first year as a player, we finished around 42nd in the country. Three years ago, we finished tied for 9th - then tied for 5th - and this year we finished tied for 3rd. The credit all goes to the team for putting in the work and next year we hope to contend for a National Title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;part-i---change-management&quot;&gt;Part I - Change Management&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first arrived, many of the things that the team did made little sense to me. I won’t go into the technical details but good &amp;amp; bad teams both do certain things and if Temple wanted to be good, there would need to be changes. As the new guy, I hadn’t earned the respect or trust of the team to change things - or even provide input towards making a change. At first, I led by example by doing all the things that I would ask the rest of the team to do. After the team saw me performing in a certain way, they began to trust me, and I earned the right to provide input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, I started slowly - pulling aside team leaders and bouncing ideas off them in private. If they thought it was a good idea, I asked them to individually reinforce or address the team as if it was their idea. I didn’t care who would receive the credit, I just wanted the team to do better - because winning is more fun than losing. As the “tips” that I was feeding to team leaders made it out to the team, I saw improvement but not as much as I would have liked. Slowly, the team became used to the idea of hearing my ideas and saw that what I was suggesting was working better than what they were previously doing. That year, we finished 9th in the country and by the last days of the National Tournament, the team put me in a position to be the defacto bench coach. Shortly after we returned from the tournament, the President of the team asked me to become the Head Coach for the next season and I accepted. Going from a peer to a coach/manager was a significant adjustment. The incoming class of players saw me as their coach but several returning upper-classmen saw me as something else. In order to get everyone bought in to what I was doing, I quickly learned that I would need the buy-in of team leaders - so that was my initial focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;part-2---the-best-way-isnt-always-the-best-way&quot;&gt;Part 2 - The “Best Way” Isn’t Always the Best Way&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shifting back to a business issue you’ve had to solve; you probably had an idea of the best way to solve the issue. Years of trial and error have caused you to come to a conclusion and you are confident that your way will undoubtedly work. As mentioned earlier, your team that needs to execute in order to have a successful outcome does not have the same experiences and skill sets that you do so there’s a chance that they will not be able to do things the way you need them done. Is it better to force them to learn how to complete the task your perfect way or is it “good enough” to allow them to create a hybrid method using your theory and their capabilities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned early in my coaching career that having everyone on the team on the same page was more important than everyone trying to do things perfectly. Michael Porter in his famous 1996 essay, “What is Strategy?” called this concept “Strategic Fit” and I believe that fit is exceedingly important in any strategy - and its importance is magnified when trying to implement change. &lt;strong&gt;I have always seen better results when 100% of the team doing something 50% “perfect” than when 50% of the team doing something 100% the way I wanted.&lt;/strong&gt; The reason for this is that when everyone is aligned, it creates harmony and builds morale. When half of the team is doing one thing and the other half is doing something else, it creates uncertainty, frustration, and chaos. In this era of instant gratification, I believe that young people aren’t as accustomed to failure as in generations past, and that in general they take it harder than I did when I was a developing player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there is uncertainty, people question leadership and lose focus on their goal. Once you have everyone on the team aligned and working together to complete the task, you can work together as a team and work at an appropriate pace to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;part-3---buy-in-is-key&quot;&gt;Part 3 - Buy-In is Key&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know of three ways to create buy in and they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dictating&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allowing the team to come up with their own solutions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaborating and coming up with a plan together
I believe that all three have their place and a good coach knows when to use each one of the three. Overusing or misusing any one of these methods can have serious negative consequences for your team, so be careful with which one or ones you choose to go with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dictating&lt;/strong&gt;, usually followed up with threats. “If you don’t do this, that will happen.” This is effective in a situation where action must be taken immediately. It can be also used as a last resort if the other two methods have failed or when you are struggling with buy-in and compromise isn’t an option. When coaching young people, I’ve tried to avoid dictating until its completely necessary because it tends to have the least amount of long-term effectiveness and breeds the most resentment. We have all had a boss that only dictates and almost none of us wanted to be this person when we grew up. This is the boss that everyone says yes to just to get them to stop talking “at” you but when they leave the room people roll their eyes or talk about them behind their back. My goal as a coach/mentor/manager is to help get all my teams to a place where I no longer need to dictate and threaten. Once everyone has bought in and is on the same page, dictating no longer becomes necessary. During the change management process, a good coach knows that dictating is a card that should be played rarely in those few situations that warrant playing it. The questions I always ask myself before going in this direction: “Is there another way?” If there is, I always try that way first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of this:&lt;/em&gt; One of the members of my team broke the rules in a way that negatively impacted another team financially. Without getting into too much detail, when the situation came to my attention, I told (dictated to) the team that we were going to come clean and make the other team whole. While this decision wasn’t popular, I made the decision because it was the right thing to do and there was no room to compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allowing the team to come up with the own solution&lt;/strong&gt; should be done whenever possible because it allows the team to feel empowered and it increases morale. From my experience, the best opportunity to allow the team to come up with their own solution is for situations that will have a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;low impact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; On our team, decision like the design of the uniforms, drafting teams for scrimmages, driving routes to get to away games, etc. are made by the team because in the scheme of things, these decisions have a low impact on performance and achieving our overall goals. Good managers need to be careful not to give their team too much slack with making their own decisions - because if the team is making too many decisions without you, why do they need you there? Additionally, when the team decides on their own, they don’t have the benefit of your experience or input when formulating a solution. Before choosing this method, think about the possible impact of the decision and if there’s a good chance it will be minimal or low, consider allowing the team to make the decision without you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaborating and coming up with a plan together&lt;/strong&gt;: this is my go-to method for achieving buy-in. While it takes significantly more time than dictating and the team may not come to your “perfect way” of doing something, it has the benefits of empowering the team while allowing them to benefit from your experience. If you start with this method and reach an impasse, you can always pivot to one of the other two methods to come to decision. Typically, this method takes the most amount of time in change management because the team needs to build up their knowledge base by doing a task and then learning through trial and error. If you have a long enough timeline, I believe that the downside is far outweighed by the upside of collaboration. It’s the most likely method to result in 100% participation and it builds a positive culture of trust and communication rather than a negative culture of “It’s my way or the highway.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An example of this:&lt;/em&gt; When working in any team environment communication is key to being successful. One area where my team knows they need to improve is in on-court communication. While I suggested/dictated to the team that we needed to work on this specific area, I collaborated with them on what our communication would be. I shared with the team how my previous teams have communicated in the past. The current team didn’t agree on specific terms, so we collaborated to come up with phrases that the current team would be comfortable using. To me the impactful area in this case is that the team simply communicates effectively, and everyone uses the same terms, so we all understand the communication. Whether they call something 4, 1+3, or 2+2 doesn’t matter - so long as everyone uses the same term and they are using it at the appropriate time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;part-4---conclusion&quot;&gt;Part 4 - Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While change management and creating buy-in with today’s young people isn’t impossible, generational differences have changed the landscape of coaching and managing. Methods that were effective in the past with previous generations can cause resentment and may have the opposite of your desired effect. In order to gain buy-in, be willing to do what you ask your team to do (at least initially). When formulating a plan to make specific changes, think about the impact of the change along with the possible positive and negative consequences of selecting a specific methodology and then choose the best approach to have the greatest perceived impact.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>rx2solutions</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html">Preface As a manager and team leader, you’ve been very successful in your career and you know what has worked for you. In a given situation, you’ve seen the scenario play out two-dozen times and you know that your way works to approach a given situation. You are managing a group of Millennials and Gen Z who are approaching this problem for the first time and surprise, surprise - you aren’t seeing eye to eye with them. Maybe your way has been disrupted by new thinking or new technology. Maybe they don’t have the same experience that you do, and they simply cannot see why your way is the best or why it will work. In any event, for the team to execute effectively, you all need to be on the same page, but how do you get there?</summary></entry></feed>